Gabriel Anderson

andgate.github.io

github.com/andgate linkedin.com/in/andgate in

Objective

Highly skilled developer with 2 years of industry experience and 15 years of independent practice, seeking a frontend developer role where I can apply my ideation, relator, and strategic strengths, alongside my broad range of technical skills, to build awesome software that makes a difference in the world.

Experience

SMART Technologies

Seattle, WA

Frontend Software Developer

Aug. 2019 - Feb. 2021

- Served millions of customers on a frontend team responsible for supporting and expanding product capacity of the company's core solution, SMART Learning Suite Online.
- Attended daily team standups, collaborated with teammates over Azure DevOps and Slack.
- Projects were built to company standards, with Agile, Clean, unit tests, and code reviews.
- Authored technical design documentation on Confluence in collaboration with other development teams.
- Built and deployed projects using TeamCity, working closely with DevOps team to ensure projects were integrated into a large final product.
- Designed and developed an Android overlay widget manager, written in Kotlin with an MVVM architecture, powered by Kotlin Flow.
- Decomposed a bloated widget framework into a set of packages as NPM monorepo using Lerna, to enable students to use the framework.
- Built an iOS-style calculator widget with React.
- Participated on winning team in company hackathon by contributing an elegant frontend Vue solution under a limited time constraint.

Central Washington University

Ellensburg, WA

Undergraduate Directed Research

Apr. 2019 - Mar. 2019

- Under Dr. Arne Leitart, explored theories to develop more a efficient, parameterized approximation algorithm for the (Connected) r-Domination problem for unweighted and undirected graphs.
- New theories were explored on whiteboard and paper exclusively.

Central Washington University

Jan. 2019 - Mar. 2019

Teaching Assistant

Ellensburg, WA

- Graded homework assignments for Algorithm Analysis, taught by Dr. Boris Kovalerchuk.
- Graded homework assignments for Introduction to Graph Algorithms, taught by Dr. Arne Leitart.
- Assisted students during computer science lab hours for both classes.

Education

Central Washington University

Ellensburg, WA

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Minor in Mathematics

Sept. 2017 - Mar. 2019

Graduated Magna Cum Laude

3.7 GPA

Projects

Alonzo

github.com/andgate/alonzo

• Lambda calculus interpreter and repl written in Haskell.

solid-orbit

github.com/andgate/solid-orbit

• Published NPM package with solid-js hooks and components that provide an orbit-js data-layer.

Mandelbulb Explorer

github.com/andgate/mandelbulb

- Raytracer with signed-distance field for mandelbulb written in C++ and GLSL.
- SFML was used to provide interactivity.

Skills

- Languages:
 - o Proficient: Javascript, Typescript, CSS, HTML, JSON, Java, Kotlin, C, C++, Haskell
 - Familiar: C#, Swift, Python, GLSL
- Frameworks: Node, React, Vue, Solid, Kotlin Flow, OpenGL
- Methodologies: Scrum, Clean, OOP, FP
- Technologies: Android, Git, NPM, Webpack, Babel, Lerna, Docker, Bash, Emacs, VSCode, NixOS